Kobato. 17 TL
“…The Mysterious Lifeform, #2”
01 eyecatch}
We’re having a bazaar at Yomogi Preschool today!
Please come take a look!
Squish?
Could that be you, Ioryogi-san?
Do you know anyone else who looks like this?
Of course it’s me.
Don’t keep your hand on me like that!
Y-Yes!
Ko… ba…
Ioryogi-san?
Ioryogi-san!
Are you taking a nap in the middle of the road?
If you’re sleepy, you should go back home first so you can use the futon.
I’m… I’m…
I’m not napping!
What happened to you, Ioryogi-san?
Why do you even ask?!
Can’t you tell just by looking at me?
What?
Ummmm…
Ioryogi-san, you look kind of muddy!
Grow a brain already!
Anyway, listen to me!
It’s getting really dark and cloudy.
It’ll be okay.
I’m sure it’ll get sunny.
I hope so.
Ioryogi-san?
I’ll bring something that’ll really sell.
Thank you!
Yeah right.
I don’t have anything like that!
I’m just tired of always pretending to be a stuffed animal at the preschool.
I’m gonna head to that bear’s place and eat Baumkuchen until I’m stuffed!
It’s always in the weirdest places.
One long!
Okay!
Four slices please!
Is the short piece ready yet?
One coffee please!
Yes, yes, slices for three, coming right up!
Is mine done yet?
Please wait a moment!
It’s getting made right now.
Slices for six all done!
What about the long?
Hold on a moment.
Two more minutes.
Business sure is booming, huh?
Yeah, I came up with a great idea.
And having another worker is important!
Let’s make some variations next time!
Like with chocolate.
Not a bad idea.
Let’s keep ’em coming!
You two seem to be fitting in well.
I didn’t know if it’d work out at first, but it’s like I’m riding the tide now.
My sarcasm doesn’t even work on you anymore.
Huh?
Nothing.
Oh, yeah!
We’ve started a home delivery service too!
For you.
Oh, from Bear’s Baumkuchen Shop?
I’ve been waiting for this.
Thanks for everything.
Don’t mention it.
You’re not the usual bird. A newcomer?
No.
I see, a part-timer?
There was a time when I was doing a lot of part-time work too.
I was getting quite the workload from my pushy employers.
Anything else you have to say?
Bye then.
Oh yeah, that’s right.
I once went to this labyrinthian mansion.
It was such a mysterious place with a bunch of weird rooms.
Seeing you guys so into this right now,
I’m close to completely forgetting who you guys used to be.
This body isn’t bad, you know.
Although it has a little too much fur.
As long as I’m careful, things work out.
It’s scary to think about how you get used to it.
I feel like I’ve been like this since birth!
Really… These days it seems like it was just a dream.
For us, it seems more like a nightmare.
It feels like it’s been forever since then.
That’s true.
When I think about it now, we never really stood a chance of winning.
We picked the wrong opponent.
It was a completely one-sided fight.
It didn’t take much to bring us down.
I felt like I stepped on someone back then…
Who was it?
That was me.
Genko-sama?! I-I’m so sorry!
It’s over already.
Back then, we didn’t even have time
to get upset over something like that.
Oh, don’t say anything!
No matter how much you’re not convinced,
the law is the law.
For now, we have to keep making baumkuchen
and wait for things to simmer down.
Right?
We were so close back then.
We weren’t close!
This is where you’re supposed to repent!
You mustn’t speak or even think that you were close!
Exactly!
If we try to pull something against the Celestial World again,
we won’t get away with just being turned into bears and birds!
I’m sure I’d end up a teddy bear!
And this guy would just be bird food!
I-I don’t want that!
It’s not fair that you’re the one
who gets to be a cute character!
In any case, you definitely
shouldn’t stir up any trouble.
Got it?
Wait, huh?
Don’t eat that!
That’s our precious merchandise!
All I got in the end was one box.
What a stingy bear.
Now that I’ve gotten something
sweet, I’d like something salty next.
And then after something salty, I’ll have baumkuchen again.
Is there anything salty around?
Guess not.
Something with soy sauce would be
good. I’m really up for something salty.
Yeah…
Something that’ll give my stomach a good kick.
What’re you doing?!
Sorry, I missed it!
Huh? The ball came back.
That’s weird.
Whatever.
Geez, all these freaking kids…
What’s so fun about playing around with a ball?
What the heck is this?!
What the heck happened?
Hey, stop it!
I’m not your food!
Hey, who’s that?
This is mine, you know!
You’re not good enough for this baumkuchen!
If you don’t stop this now, I’ll burn you to a crisp…
Hey!
Stop it!
Come on!
Damn it! You guys!
Even if… I die… I won’t… give you… this box!
Huh?!
Water’s no good!
This is pretty tough.
I might cough up something besides fire doing this.
My body’s heavy.
It just never lets up.
I’ll dry up in a jiffy with that.
Drying machines are more intense than I thought.
Wait a sec… where am I?
Is that true?
Yeah, that grocery…
You know, I sure am hungry…
No, no, no, no, no.
I’ll take my time eating this once I get back.
I’m not some kid that can’t wait till he’s done with his errand…
I can’t, I can’t, I can’t!
Wh-What’s this delicious smell?
What the heck is that mysterious lifeform?
Welcome to Mocona Land!
You young ladies and gentlemen.
Don’t get lost while you enjoy yourselves here!
Now then, go out there and have fun!
I ended up in a strange place.
Oh, right!
That delicious smell…
It all looks so yummy!
Ow, ow, ow…
Now I’ve done it!
I’m sorry!
Huh? Hey, wait!
Excuse me!
Damn it!
I’m a stuffed animal, but I’m not…
I’ve gotta get out of here!
Otherwise someone’s going to take the baumkuchen!
Where is this?
What’re they doing?
I’ll get you whichever one you like.
Wait, don’t tell me…
Papa, get me that one!
All right!
Th-This is…!
Yay!
A shooting gallery?!
Here.
Isn’t this great?
Papa, I want that blue doggie!
Let’s see…
That one, right?
Me?!
So close!
I missed!
Hahaha, as if!
This time I’ll get it!
Crap!
This is…!
On course for a direct hit!
You missed again!
So close!
Strange.
All right, I’ll get it for sure next time.
Did it just move?
It didn’t move!
You just suck.
Damn it, that just makes me want to get it more!
Papa, you can do it!
All right, I’ll get it no matter what!
I wonder if you’ll get it this time!
Damn it!
Be a nice man and give up instead of getting upset!
So close!
I’ll go for it too!
We’ll help too!
Demons!
We can’t get it!
Leave it to me.
Despite my appearances, long ago people used to call me
the dreaded “Gallery Shooter Okana-chan.”
Who the freaking hell are you?!
Oh my.
It’s no good if it doesn’t drop.
What?!
All right!
Then let’s all combine our powers!
Don’t!!!
Why won’t that blue one fall?
Like hell I’d let myself become some kid’s plaything!
I did it!
Congratulations!
Huh?
It’s gone.
I can’t find it.
Huh?
It did fall just now, right?
Yeah, we all saw it!
What happened?
That was terrible.
I should be fine after coming this far.
So that’s what happened.
So? The posters you put up were torn down,
and you’ve been running around all this time?
But no one was coming to the bazaar.
Well, it’s such a small event, after all.
It was crazier to expect a lot of people to come to a bazaar at a preschool.
If I had known this would happen, maybe it would’ve been better
if I hadn’t brought up the idea of the bazaar.
That’s not true.
What’s important is that you set out to do what you said you would.
Even if there are bumps in the road, you shouldn’t give up.
Yes.
Even if you get drenched in
water and attacked by snipers.
Yes?
Oh, it’s nothing.
Well, what’s important is doing it.
Don’t feel so dejected just
because people aren’t coming.
Welcome!
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much!
Welcome back, Kobato-chan!
You’re late!
Look, look, we’ve sold so much!
The teru teru bozu are selling too!
Thanks to you, Kobato-san,
I got an unexpectedly good find.
How long are you going to just stand there?
S-Sorry!
Look at all the customers. We need more help.
So…
Hurry and help out too.
Yes!
Kobato-chan.
Thank you so much.
It’s thanks to you that all these people came.
N-No, I didn’t…!
Look.
Everyone’s enjoying themselves.
It’s thanks to you, Kobato-chan.
Kobato-chan.
Doumoto-san!
Thank you for taking the time to come here!
You’re welcome.
I had a lot of fun.
That’s great!
But I would’ve liked to have bought something directly from you.
O-Oh yeah!
I had a stall too!
What happened to it?
They aren’t selling.
Well, that’s natural.
It’s not like anyone would
want this mysterious lifeform
when you can’t even tell if it’s
a chicken, penguin, sheep or what.
Then I’ll buy one.
Really?
Yeah.
Thank you!
It is a rather unique sense of taste.
Just what I’d expect from you, Kobato-chan.
Is it a rabbit?
D-Doumoto-san!
Today was a wonderful day!
It was terrible for me!
Really?
Yeah!
Weren’t you listening to my story?!
Um…
Really?
“Really”, my ass!
Well, I did protect what’s important to me, so I guess it’s all right.
I’ll scarf it down as soon as I get back.
No, I’ll take my time to eat that.
“That”?
That.
By “that”, what do you mean?
Huh?
It’s gone.
My baumkuchen is gone!
Fine then. We’re going back to the preschool to get it.
Oh, we sold that baumkuchen right away.
Y-Y-You did what?!
That thing you said would really
sell was that baumkuchen, right?
Thank you so much!
Your score for today was 80 points
for your passion towards the bazaar.
And…
Including my disappointment, -300 points!
Why, Ioryogi-san?!
Are you disappointed because of me?
Then I’ll apologize!
Apologizing won’t solve anything!
Th-Then I’ll give you one of my cute rabbits!
It’ll make you feel better!
I don’t need it!
Th-Then I’ll give you an extra one!
I said I don’t need it!
Then I’ll give you this cute bear and sheep!
I can’t tell what they are in the first place!
They’re all mysterious lifeforms!
How mean, Ioryogi-san!